<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Project name="Antistasi">
		<Package name="Antistasi">
				<Key ID="STR_CLOSE">
						<Original>Close</Original>
						<Russian>Закрыть</Russian>
				</Key>
				<Key ID="STR_TUTORIAL_ACTION">
						<Original>Tutorial</Original>
						<Russian>Справочная</Russian>
				</Key>
				<Key ID="STR_TUTO_TITLE">
						<Original>TUTORIAL</Original>
						<Russian>СПРАВОЧНАЯ</Russian>
				</Key>
				<Key ID="STR_TUTO_TITLE1">
						<Original>1 Starting Out</Original>
						<Russian>1. Перед тем как начать</Russian>
				</Key>
				<Key ID="STR_TUTO_TEXT1">
						<Original>&lt;br/&gt;
						Antistasi Altis simulates the FIA fighting a guerilla war against a convention force, the AAF, in an attempt take control of Altis. Because the focus of this scenario is a smaller more nimble force (the player) taking on a much larger more powerful force, non-convention and asymmetric tactics must be employed to be successful. This is especially true early on. Here are some tips for Antistasi players who are just beginning their quest to retake Altis (read below).
						</Original>
				</Key>
				<Key ID="STR_TUTO_TITLE2">
						<Original>1.2 Quick Note about Saving</Original>
				</Key>
				<Key ID="STR_TUTO_TEXT2">
						<Original>
						&lt;br/&gt;
						The standard ARMA3 save feature is &lt;t font='PuristaBold'&gt;NOT SUPPORTED&lt;/t&gt; by Antistasi. The amount of data that needs to be retained to properly load Antistasi is not something the default ARMA3 save file can store efficiently. As you progress through the campaign the standard ARMA3 save files will get larger and load times will increase until files get corrupted or no longer load. It is &lt;t font='PuristaBold'&gt;REQUIRED&lt;/t&gt; that you always use the Antistasi Persistent Save feature to truly preserve your progress. Some players have reported success with always persistent saving before exiting ARMA3 but using the standard ARMA3 save/load as an interim progress checkpoint instead of respawning at the HQ when dying.
						&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
						&lt;t font='PuristaBold'&gt;If you try and hit resume then you will notice some features like the Y menu and groups buttons not working. You should always hit restart and then load persistent save when you enter the game.&lt;/t&gt;
						&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
						&lt;t color='#aaaaaa' size='0.89' align='right'&gt;Note: &lt;t font='PuristaBold'&gt;ALL&lt;/t&gt; players are required to save via the persistent save option &lt;br/&gt;available at the FIA Headquarters' map to save and load.&lt;/t&gt;
						</Original>
				</Key>
				<Key ID="STR_TUTO_TITLE3">
						<Original>1.3 Headquarters Location</Original>
				</Key>
				<Key ID="STR_TUTO_TEXT3">
						<Original>&lt;br/&gt;
						Choosing a good place to station your HQ is a lot more difficult than you’d think. If you’re just starting your first game of Antistasi it’s best to just stick with the default HQ location as that is safe yet not super far from potential mission sites. Eventually, however, you will need to move your HQ further into Altis to get closer to enemy-supported towns and AAF assets. When you do decide to move your HQ, take the following factors into consideration.
						&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
						&lt;t font='PuristaBold'&gt;Out of sight, out of mind.&lt;/t&gt; You want to be close to AAF assets and enemy-supported towns but not within range of enemy patrols. The enemy will dispatch patrols sometimes up to a kilometer away from anything they control (including towns). These patrols may just be one or two men with rifles that are easy enough to fight. But patrols can also include MRAPs or trucks filled with infantry. If you’re off on a mission when the base is discovered, it may not be possible to get back in time before Petros takes a bullet to the everywhere… Furthermore, if an enemy is within 500 meters of your base you will not be able to recruit units or squads. If the base is under attack, whatever you’ve recruited up until that point is all you have to defend your HQ.
						&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
						&lt;t color='#aaaaaa' size='0.89' align='right'&gt;Tip: Enemies do not really patrol the high seas unless very near to a SeaPort. Use that to your advantage and hug the coastline to avoid trouble. Most roads stay away from the shore and there are often mountains in between the coast and the enemy that can further conceal your HQ.&lt;/t&gt;
						&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
						&lt;t font='PuristaBold'&gt;Balance out having both AAF assets and enemy-controlled towns nearby.&lt;/t&gt; Missions requiring you to assassinate an officer in an AAF base will end very badly early on in the game. The easiest missions to start out with are simply gathering support for your cause in the local villages. Delivering supplies and rescuing refugees are not particularly difficult even in the early game and they go a long way in winning the hearts and minds of the citizens of Altis.
						&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
						&lt;t font='PuristaBold'&gt;Beware of roads.&lt;/t&gt; Even though units you recruit will spawn on roads and it is much easier to drive to HQs situated near roads, roads are also used by the enemy. Study the routes most convoys will take. Supply and Money convoys will typically depart from a base and then head to an enemy-controlled town. If your HQ is nearby to road that is directly in between a base and a town, you’re much more likely to encounter enemy traffic. Again this will probably include APCs and MRAPs which you do NOT want around your base, especially early on.
						&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
						&lt;t font='PuristaBold'&gt;Air Assault counter-attacks&lt;/t&gt; are a very serious threat to your HQ. A location that is perfectly hidden from patrols and convoys may still be very exposed to enemy air assaults, even if that assault did not intend to find/attack your HQ. As you capture areas and flee from enemy counter-attacks, sometimes the enemy will send UAVs or attack helis to assault the base in addition to the regular complement of infantry. If they do this and your HQ is within a kilometer or two of the area you just attacked, it’s entirely possible the HQ will be spotted and assaulted. Aircraft fly around their intended target with a wide berth, and if a UAV spots your HQ from above, it will still launch ordinance at it even if it is kilometers away from its objective. Make sure your HQ is hidden well by tree cover if you plan assault anything within a couple kilometers.
						&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
						&lt;t font='PuristaBold'&gt;Flight path of enemy aircraft is also important.&lt;/t&gt; Just like with convoys and roads, placing your HQ between a point you assaulted and an enemy airport can be very dangerous. In Antitstasi, all enemy attacks are actually launched from a base or airport, not spawned out of nowhere. If you place and HQ very far from where you’re fighting but the flight path for a counter-attack passes over Petros, the AAF will absolutely destroy your HQ if it is not well defended against aircraft.
						&lt;br/&gt;
						&lt;t font='PuristaBold'&gt;NATO Support&lt;/t&gt; can turn the tide of a battle and/or make your life much easier. Just like with enemy attacks, friendly support is spawned from a carrier air group waiting off the coast of Altis. If you ask for a supply drop, a helicopter will depart from its home carrier loaded with supplies for you. If you place your HQ in between the carrier and many enemy assets, it’s very likely this poor helicopter will get clobbered with anti-aircraft fire and never make it to you. This is part of the reason why starting in the bottom left corner of the map is a good idea for new players – it’s very close to the NATO carrier and their support options have a very high chance of reaching you in that part of the island.
						</Original>
				</Key>
				<Key ID="STR_TUTO_TITLE4">
						<Original>1.4 Guerilla Tactics</Original>
				</Key>
				<Key ID="STR_TUTO_TEXT4">
						<Original>&lt;br/&gt;
						Ok, so you’ve placed your HQ in a good spot – let’s go blow stuff up. Before we get overzealous and try to take a major AAF base, let’s come back down to reality. You’re a small group of rebels with limited manpower and even more limited supplies. Attempting to storm and capture something as small as an enemy seaport or outpost may appear easy, but even if you are able to conquer an area like that the enemy will respond with massive overwhelming force to retake the lost position. Even with skilled players cooperating together very well, it is very likely the FIA will not have powerful enough weapons or support to hope to fend off the counterattack. The most important concept for the early stages of the game is a guerilla warrior’s mantra: &lt;t font='PuristaBold'&gt;Hit and Run!&lt;/t&gt;
						&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
						Hitting outposts and isolated/vulnerable points of interest on the map is still useful even if you cannot hold the territory you’ve taken. For starters, try to have a truck on standby or steal the enemy’s vehicles to load up equipment stores located next to the flag. When first starting out, you will have very few weapons to fight with, presenting a major disadvantage to assaulting and holding large locations. Stealing ammo, weapons, and equipment is the only way to increase the arsenal at your disposal. Quickly ambushing outposts, loading up the truck with supplies, and rushing back to base will be one of the most important things you do in the early game. One other advantage to early successful raids is garnering NATO support. NATO is a powerful organization but they’re not going to just get involved in a little war on a tiny island. You need to prove you’re worth supporting before they put their own men on the line. As you gain popular support and show that you are capable of beating the AAF, NATO will support you more and more. This will come in handy when you start using the NATO support options.
						</Original>
				</Key>
				<Key ID="STR_TUTO_TITLE5">
						<Original>1.5 Use Supporting Fire!</Original>
				</Key>
				<Key ID="STR_TUTO_TEXT5">
						<Original>&lt;br/&gt;
						Mortar squads in Antistasi Altis are cheap and they are an absolute godsend. Some missions require you to take on outposts with multiple .50 caliber gun emplacements and armor support. Bringing a few squads of infantry, ordering them to open fire, and hoping for the best will often result in disaster. Sneaking up to the base with a pair of binoculars and ordering down hellfire from above is a much more elegant solution. People can play Antistasi many different ways, but if you can afford it I would highly recommend never leaving home without a mortar detachment supporting you. The ability to call down arty when you’re pinned down or stuck on an objective is just too useful to pass up.
						&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
						A few useful tips on using mortars:
						&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
						&lt;t font='PuristaBold'&gt;Firing mortars continuously&lt;/t&gt; and in large volleys will increase the chances of counterbattery fire. Eventually the enemy will figure out where your mortar truck is and send some ordinance of their own in that area. Be careful about abusing the same truck over and over again. If you can afford multiple trucks, buy 3 or 4 units and then spread them out around the map. Losing one to triangulation and counterbattery fire will be a minor loss if your fire support is spread out.
						&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
						&lt;t font='PuristaBold'&gt;Mortars have a “barrage mode”&lt;/t&gt; that lets you cover an area with the munition type of your choosing by setting two markers on your field map. This can be useful to pulverize a hardened enemy position – but also be sure to try it with smoke rounds as well to provide a large screen of advance for your troops!
						&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
						&lt;t font='PuristaBold'&gt;Mortars have a finite amount of ammunition&lt;/t&gt; UNLESS you place them next to your ammo supply box in your HQ. This essentially gives you infinite amounts of mortars (smoke and flares included). However, the biggest risk to this is giving away your position and exposing your HQ to counterbattery fire. If this happens you could lose the whole mission because your mortar team got trigger happy.
						&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
						&lt;t font='PuristaBold'&gt;Mortar teams are very small&lt;/t&gt; – only a mortar operator and a truck driver. This means they’re essentially defenseless. Be careful when moving your teams around in enemy territory. A patrol of two AAF solders can wipe out a mortar team easily.
						&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
						&lt;t font='PuristaBold'&gt;Mortars don’t have infinite range.&lt;/t&gt; Make sure you confirm that your mortars can reach your area of operation before opening fire. You can do this by beginning to place a fire order with the mortar team in question. If the message “Invalid Range” comes back when you try to select an ammunition type – you’re out of range.
						&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
						&lt;t font='PuristaBold'&gt;Physics are a thing in ARMA3.&lt;/t&gt; The further you are from your mortar team, the longer it will take for the mortars to reach their target. You can end up waiting well over a minute for rounds to reach their mark. Careful timing and planning needs to be taken if using smoke to cover an assault… 
						</Original>
				</Key>
				<Key ID="STR_TUTO_TITLE6">
						<Original>1.6 Starting out with Missions</Original>
				</Key>
				<Key ID="STR_TUTO_TEXT6">
						<Original>&lt;br/&gt;
						Guerilla warfare is not all about ambushes and killing the bad guys. You’re fighting on behalf of the citizens of Altis so you need to help them out as well. Doing missions in nearby towns is a great way to gather support and occasionally other bonuses as well. Here are some good missions to start out trying:
						&lt;br/&gt;
						&lt;br/&gt;- &lt;t font='PuristaBold'&gt;City Supplies&lt;/t&gt; (Logistics Mission)
						&lt;br/&gt;- &lt;t font='PuristaBold'&gt;Refugees Evac&lt;/t&gt; (Rescue Mission)
						&lt;br/&gt;- &lt;t font='PuristaBold'&gt;Capture the Outpost&lt;/t&gt; (Conquer Mission)
						&lt;br/&gt;- &lt;t font='PuristaBold'&gt;Kill the Traitor&lt;/t&gt; (Assassination Mission)
						&lt;br/&gt;- &lt;t font='PuristaBold'&gt;Destroy the Radio Tower/Ammo Truck&lt;/t&gt; (Destroy Mission)
						&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
						These missions can be specifically requested from Petros by using his action menu. A screen will appear asking what type of mission you would like to do (this is the value in parenthesis next to each mission name). Note that there are different missions in each type, some of which are far harder. For instance, rescuing refugees from a town is much easier than rescuing prisoners from an AAF base. Avoid missions that ask you to do something in or around a major AAF installation! They are always more difficult than operating in towns. More information about what each mission entails can be found in a subsequent section.
						</Original>
				</Key>
		</Package>
</Project>
